准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
月光水母
猎捕记
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
现在播出  水母迷会谈
And now "The Jellyson Group"
水母迷会谈
晚上好  欢迎收看水母迷会谈
Good evening and welcome to "The Jellyson Group,"
裤头村最强捉水母节目  仅此一家
Bikini Bottom's best and only show about jellyfishing
今晚的嘉宾有水母时尚记者
My guests tonight
are jellyfishing fashion journalist
法布莉卡欧莱
Fabrica Olay
知名水母杂技师
Famed jellyfish juggler
小丑老鱼兄
Fish-O The Clown
还有某个叫海绵宝宝的东西
And something called a SpongeBob
今晚谈论的主题是月光水母
Tonight we will be discussing the moon jellyfish
每25年一遇
Only seen once every 25 years
即将迁徙经过裤头村
will soon be migrating through Bikini Bottom
容我插一句
If I can just interrupt
根本没证据能表明这种水母真实存在
there's no evidence this jellyfish even exists
有谁看到了  更何况又有谁捉到了呢
Has anyone seen it, much less caught it?
海参凯文
Kevin C. Cucumber
世上最伟大的水母捕手
the greatest jellyfisher who ever lived
捉到过月光水母
caught the moon jellyfish
放他广为流传的视频  看猎捕全过程
Roll his famous moon catching clip
我捉到了
I caught it
捉到月光水母了
I caught the moon jellyfish
我爱捉水母
I love jellyfishing
那视频是假的
That video is a fake
我觉得是真的啊
Well, it looked real to me
水母是真的
That fish is real--
那是造假
It's a fake
耍诈
A ruse
穿大鞋的笨小丑
You big-shoed buffoon
眼不瞎都看得出来
Anyone could see it
明明就有月光水母
The moon jellyfish is a fact
别吵了
Stop
水母货真价实
It's not fake
我一定会捉到月光水母  向你们证明
and I'll prove it to you by catching the moon jellyfish
就跟凯文当年一个样
just like Kevin did
暂停
我先前跟你怎么说的  小蜗
What did I tell you, Gary?
要是能找来凯文帮我忙
Maybe if I can get Kevin to help me
我就能有机会捉到月光水母了
I'll have a chance to catch that moon jellyfish
我知道要上哪去找凯文
And I know just where to find Kevin
水母捕手
就在水母捕手俱乐部
At the Jellyspotters Clubhouse
你好
Hello
我在找
I'm looking for--
凯文  真的是你吗
Kevin, is it really you?
我配不上你
I'm not worthy
你好啊  配不上你
Hey there, Not Worthy
我是派大星
I'm Patrick
派大星
Patrick?
你成水母捕手俱乐部部长了吗
You're the president of the Jellyspotters Club?
那当然
Sure am
大家抽了签
We drew straws
吸管
我第一个把签全吃了
and I was the first one to eat them all
太好了
That's great
海参凯文在吗
Is Kevin Cucumber here?
吸管
你是说那位书呆海黄瓜吗
You mean the guy that looks like a nerdy pickle?
俱乐部好几年前就把他踢出去了
He got kicked out of the club years ago
早就神隐了
and mysteriously disappeared
谁都不知道他在哪
No one knows where he is
不过你想找他的话
But if you want to find him
这是他现在的住址
here's his current address
林中小屋路123号
123 Shack in the Woods Lane
谢谢派大星
Thank you, Patrick
叫我部长派大星才对  老兄
That's President Patrick to you, Sonny Jim
可以帮我续杯吗
Can I get a refill on these?
吸管
树林到了
Well, these are the woods
眼前也就只有这一条小路
and this is the only lane I see
一定就是这里了
This must be the place
在吗
Hello?
凯文
Kevin?
你在吗
You here?
该去遛遛了  金盏花小姐
Time for walkies, Miss Marigold
阿姨你好
Hello, ma'am
我在找海参凯文
I'm looking for Kevin C. Cucumber
你有看到他吗
Have you seen him?
凯文
Kevin?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
凯文
Kevin
你来我林中秘密耻辱洞干嘛
What are you doing here at my secret forest shame hole?
在找你啊  笨蛋
Looking for you, silly
我要向大师请教秘诀  猎捕月光水母
I need some moon jellyfish-catching tips
from the master
大师
Master?
曾经可能拥有过的技能  我全都没了
I've lost any skills I might have once had
连一般的水母都忘了怎么捉了
I don't remember how to catch a regular jelly
就连怎么着凉感冒都不会了
I don't even remember how to catch a cold
捉
没关系  凯文
Well, don't worry, Kevin
我可以帮你东山再起
I can get you back in shape
然后一起捉到月光水母
Then we can catch the moon jelly
你就可以重回巅峰了
and then you'll be on top again
就跟以前一个样
Just like the old days
是这样吗
You think so?
值得一试
It's worth a try
谢了  海绵宝宝
Thanks, SpongeBob
这是我多年以来最美好的一天
This is the best day I've had in years
还是先帮你打理干净好了
Maybe we'll clean you up first
凯文回来了  宝贝
Kevin is back, baby
水母田
既然帮你打理好了
Now that you're looking the part
那现在就来帮你重拾捉水母技能吧
let's shake the rust
off those jellyfishing skills, shall we?
还是先从稍微简单点的起步吧
Maybe we'll start with something a little easier
小水母
Jelly babies
好  要简单得不止一点点
OK, maybe something a lot easier
去捉吧  凯文
Now, go ahead, Kevin
甩出
Take your--
最强一网
best swing
成功了
I did it
我又会捉水母了
I'm a jellyfisher again
水母田
现在来动真格了
OK, now for the real deal
捉月光水母的第一步是什么
What's step one in catching the moon jellyfish?
这个我会
I know this one
等待月光降临  水母现形
Wait for the moon to come out so we can see it
第一步答得好
Good step one
要来了
Here it comes
凯文  第二步是什么
OK, Kevin, what's step two?
凯文
Kevin?
让水母追我们  用疲劳战术拖累它
Tire the moon jelly out by getting it to chase us
一定就是第二步了吧
That must be step two, huh?
根本没有第二步
There is no step two
我压根不会捉月光水母
I don't know how to catch a moon jellyfish
我特地去摄影棚  造假猎捕过程
I faked the moon catching on a soundstage
这样大家才会说我酷
so people would think I was cool
捉到了
I got it
你机会来了
This is your chance
趁机捉到它  让你酷回来
to catch it and really be cool
快躲进去
Quick, in here
最好的办法就是包围它
Our best bet is to surround it
你左边包围
You go left
我右边包围
I'll go right
两面包夹捉到它
We'll catch it between us
务必记住  关键就在于隐秘行动
And remember, stealth is key
警察
咱大白天还得上班呢
Some of us work in the morning
拜托
Come on
是月光水母
It's the moon jellyfish
快看看啊
Look at that
感觉好像追不到水母  海绵宝宝
I don't think we're going to
catch up to that jellyfish, SpongeBob
膝盖都累坏了
My knees are getting tired
追不到就设陷阱
If we can't outrun it, maybe we can trap it
但是得要来点诱饵
But we'll need some bait
月光水母喜欢吃什么
What would a moon jellyfish like to eat?
起司
Cheese
不许动  月光水母
Freeze, moon jelly
束手就擒吧
Prepare to be caught
月光暗下去了
We're losing the light
月光水母快消失了
The moon jelly's going to disappear
暗下去是吗
Losing the light, you say?
那你们就应该需要再来一点点
Maybe you could use a little
月光
moonlight
屁股
快看  起效了
Look, it's working
再来一点月光
We need more moonlight
捉到它了
We caught him
我们成功了  凯文
We did it, Kevin
我们成功了
We did it
抱歉  海绵宝宝
Sorry, SpongeBob
才没我们这回事
But there's no we about it
月光水母可是我自个儿捉的
I'm the sole catcher of the moon jellyfish
什么
Wha?
等一下
Wait a minute
这是要去哪
Where are we going?
你要带我上哪去
Where are you taking me?
月光水母要去哪
Where's the moon jelly going?
回家  派大星
Home, Patrick
回家
Home
25年后它才会回来
Until it comes back in 25 years, that is
我恨捉水母
I hate jellyfishing
历史笑传
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
珊迪  再几步就能看到给你的惊喜了
OK, Sandy, your surprise is just a few more steps away
天啊  我等不及要
Gosh, fellas, I can't wait to--
惊喜
Surprise
裤头村历史博物馆
礼品店
The Museum of Bikini Bottom History
你们怎么知道要带我来这里的
How'd y'all know to take me here?
你给我们送了邀请函
You gave us these invitations
我太高兴了
And boy am I glad I did
等不及要来学习
I'm just itching to learn
裤头村源远流长的历史了
all about the rich history of Bikini Bottom
而且还要记笔记
And I will be taking notes
我的研究要刊登在
My research is going to be featured
科研期刊海军报上面
in a scientific journal, "The Naval Gazette"
海军报
我就爱盯着肚脐眼看
I love gazing at my navel
[ gazing（凝视）与 gazette（报纸）谐音
navel（肚脐）与 naval（海军的）谐音 ]
嗨
Hi
那还等什么呢
Well, what are we waiting for?
请出示门票
Tickets, please
给你看吧
Here you go
来看看
Let's see here
一张  两张
One, two--
忘记数到哪了
gee, I lost my place
裤头村
最老的保安
快看  第一样文物
Look, the first artifact
裤头村最老的保安
Bikini Bottom's oldest security guard
这种老机器人早该清灰了
They should dust these old robots
不识字吗
Can't you read?
眼观手不动
上面写眼观手不动
It says no touching
抱歉
Sorry
好了  年轻小伙们
All right, youngsters
请进
In you go
不准惹麻烦
Now, don't cause any trouble
不然就尝尝我的厉害
or you'll have to answer to me
还在吗
Hello?
欢迎来到裤头村创立以前的远古时期
Welcome to the ancient past
before Bikini Bottom was Bikini Bottom
据大家说这里的展品
They say the exhibits here
最晚可以追溯到万千年前
date back at least one gazillion years
确定有万千那个数吗
You sure about that math?
大家数学可好了
They do math good
裤头峰
快看这里
Look here, fellas
数百万年前  这片土地
Millions of years ago, this here land
叫做裤头峰
was called Bikini Top
自然侵蚀导致其海拔逐渐下降
The elevation was lowered due to natural erosion
才没有这回事
That's not how it happened
放心  珊迪
Don't worry, Sandy
我们来告诉你事实真相
We'll tell you the true story
没错
Yeah
是这样的
It goes like this
万千年前
A gazillion years ago
有个巨型大锚砸中了裤头峰
Bikini Top was hit by a humongous anchor
大锚把整座山压平到了海底
The anchor flattened the hill
to the bottom of the ocean
所以裤头村的名字就是这么来的
which is why it's called Bikini Bottom
底
然后由于大锚太重了
And then the anchor was so heavy
一大堆建筑拔地而起
that a bunch of buildings
got popped up out of the ground
裤头村
Bikini Bottom
所以你们是想说
You mean to tell me
我们在参观的这个大锚博物馆
the very anchor we're standing inside now
创造了裤头村吗
is the one that created Bikini Bottom?
好
Yup
懂了
I see
[ bull（胡扯） ]
看来这一层展厅
Looks like this floor
展现出了裤头村的拓荒时代
covers Bikini Bottom's old pioneer days
是真正的古董石头
A genuine antique rock
拓荒老祖先就用石头骑行了好几里远
The pioneers used to ride these babies for miles
我想试试看
I want to try
驾
Giddyup
冷静
Calm down
我来救你
I gotcha
不准玩套索
No trick ropin'
小混混一群
Darn hooligans
抱歉了
Sorry, sir
珊迪看好了  拓荒时代里
Look, Sandy, in the old days
拓荒老祖先在自家产地给乳海胆挤奶
the pioneers used to
milk dairy urchins on their homesteads
那时生活简单又淳朴
It was a simple, honest life
贪念全无
without an ounce of greed
又挤了满满一桶  贝西
Another full pail, Bessie
肯定可以换不少好货
I reckon I can barter for quite a bit with this
就换个更厚的手套好了
Maybe for some thicker gloves
但是拓荒老祖先必须当心
But the pioneers have to watch out
肮脏发臭的亡命徒
for those dirty, stinky outlaws
不会吧
Oh, no
龌龊帮来了
It's the Grungy Gang
怪不得哪里味道怪怪的
I knew something smelled fishy
我们要来夺走你家宝贝小海胆
We're here to take that valuable little urchin
快拱手让出来
off your hands
拱蟹爪才对
Claws
想得美  肮脏大坏蛋
Not so fast, you filthy felons
幸好海绵警长与海星副手警官
Fortunately, Sheriff Pants and Deputy Star
为这片土地带来了治安
brought law and order to the land
我们要来让你们改邪归正
We're here to clean up your act
抓住他们  小的们
Get 'em, boys
泡泡
Bubbles
治安变好  商业随之而来
And with law came commerce
于是裤头村第一家餐厅开张了
Thus Bikini Bottom's first restaurant was opened
蟹奶王
The Krusty Kreamery
纪念奶袋
要来点纪念奶吗
Care for some souvenir milk?
我不渴
I'm not thirsty
谢了
Thanks
不要拉倒
Suit yourself
我们一定是踏进了
I reckon we've stepped into
裤头村的工业革命时代
Bikini Bottom's Industrial Revolution era
C型
C型船
A Model C Boat?
[ 同名原型车为福特制造
福特发明了第一条汽车制造流水线 ]
上面写着
Says here--
别念了  珊迪
Don't read that, Sandy
我们来跟你讲讲真正的故事
We'll tell you the real story
海绵宝宝  什么故事
SpongeBob, what's the story?
裤头村的工业巨头  泡芙先生
Well, Bikini Bottom's own titan of industry, Mr. Puff
开发了第一条汽船流水线  大获成功
ran the first successful boat assembly line
让工人尽可能高效工作非常重要
It was important for every worker
to perform as efficiently as possible
加快五号流水线
Speed up line number five
正在加快五号流水线
Speeding up line number five
工人有时会被工作缠得脱不开身
Sometimes they'd get
a little too caught up in their work
看好了
Watch this
但是泡芙先生可精明了
But being a shrewd industrialist
在隔壁也开了一家医院
Mr. Puff also owned the hospital next door
急诊
哔哔
Beep, beep
先给我等一下
Now hold it just a darn minute
[ screwball（荒诞） ]
这种荒诞故事不可能是真的
Ain't no way these screwball stories are true
我看看牌子
Let me read that plaque
工业巨头
"Titan of industry"
流水线
"Assembly line"
受伤
"Injuries"
隔壁开医院
"Hospital next door"
哔哔
"Beep beep"?
好家伙
Well, twist my tail
还真是
Y'all were right
早说了吧
Told ya
哔哔
Beep beep
裤头村的历史果然多彩多姿
I knew Bikini Bottom's history would be colorful
但答案太少  反而新问题又来了
but I'm starting to have more questions than answers
也许可以去顶楼的这个问号
Maybe this question mark on the top floor
就可以回答你所有问题了
is where you get your questions answered
这些忘记按了
You forgot to push these
迷幻海时代
Psychedelic Sea era
[ 迷幻摇滚：摇滚乐流派
深受嬉皮士文化影响 ]
深海迪斯科时代
Deep Disco era
新浪潮白痴时代
New Wave Nitwits era
[ 新浪潮：运用合成器和电子元素
在MV中表现独特视觉风格 ]
四处探险时代
Nautical Nonsense era
这博物馆也太怪了吧
This sure is a weird museum
这里应该是幽灵展厅吧
I guess this is the ghost exhibit
这里应该还在施工  派大星
I think it's under construction, Patrick
等不及要看博物馆放幽灵了
I can't wait till they put the ghosts in
先等一下
Wait a second
难道这是假牙佩戴器
Is this a denture applicator?
骨科喷气靴
Orthopedic jet boots
原子成人尿布射线
The atomic adult diaper ray
我们是成人
We're adults
未来裤头村
到底怎么回事
What in tarnation?
这可不是一般的未来
This ain't no regular future, fellas
是助步器老头统治的未来
This is a future ruled by Old Man Walker
安静
滚出我草坪
没错  小混混
That's right, you hooligans
我说了眼观手不动
I said no touching
抱歉
Sorry
你们三个看到的太多了
You three have seen too much
现在我要来抓住你们
and now I'm going to get ya
站好别动
Stay right there
快跑
Run
求你了  助步器老头
Please, Old Man Walker
我们不会泄露未来的事
We won't tell nobody about the future
大家听我说  我们看到了未来
Hey, everybody, we've seen the future
但那是天机不可泄露
but it's a secret
助步器老头必将把你们全统治了
Old Man Walker will rule you all
礼品店
裤头村的过去和未来就这样全看完了
Well, there goes Bikini Bottom's entire past and future
珊迪  所以你说怎么样
So, Sandy, what'd you think?
我还是将信将疑
I'm still skeptical
裤头村的过去太疯狂了
Bikini Bottom's past was a bit too nuts
我这松鼠可受不住
for this old squirrel
不过  起码裤头村现在挺正常的
But hey, at least Bikini Bottom is normal now
对  基本算正常
Yep, totally normal